Zachary L. Jacobs

CONTACT INFORMATION

3821 Ashley Terrace; Yukon, OK 73099 Cell: 405.370.9905 Home: 405.494.7266

Email: zachiacobs@outlook.com

PROFILE

Objective I am a 14-year veteran of the U.S. Air Force looking to maximize my varied skills learned therein – and in the mass

communications field - to become a productive and dynamic Social Media Strategist for VI Marketing and Branding.

Availability Immediately

KEY SKILLS

Proficient or familiar with a vast array of concepts, technologies and computer programs, including:

Typing (>60 wpm) Associated Press Style/Format Sony Vegas

Avid

On-Screen Script Reading Microsoft Office Suite Adobe PhotoShop Apple Final Cut

Broadcast Writing Microsoft Publisher Adobe InDesign Public Speaking

Print/Online Format Writing Windows Movie Maker Adobe Premiere Impromptu Speaking

WORK EXPERIENCE

Journal Record Legislative Report; Oklahoma City, OK

January to May 2013

Legislative Assistant

Observed, researched and reported on committee and full legislative meetings for Oklahoma Senate and House of Representatives.

Gathered, summarized and entered information on bills and resolutions for Oklahoma Senate and House of Representatives.

Oklahoma City University; Oklahoma City, OK

Student

Part-time iob

Student Anchor/Producer/Production Assistant

August 2011 to May 2013

- Hosted, executive produced and produced media- and election-themed talk show at student television station.
- Operated and troubleshot teleprompter and studio cameras for news programs.

507th Air Refueling Wing; Tinker AFB, OK

Part- and full-time job

Public Affairs Specialist

June 2009 to August 2012 Managing editor of publication team with full responsibility for layout/design, editing, work assignments, scheduling and long-term

- planning/development of monthly eight-page-long (or greater) hardcopy and digital newsletter.
- Single-handedly redesigned newsletter from tabloid to magazine style.
- Oversaw transition from tangible publication to digital format, saving wing more than \$5,000 annually.
- Provided expert graphic layout/design software guidance/training to other office staff.
- Constantly adhered to deadlines and Associated Press Stylebook guidelines.
- Reviewed/edited photography with background training/computer programs for quality, composition and context within news stories/publications, both internal and external.

KOCO-TV Eyewitness News 5; Oklahoma City, OK

Part-time job

Engineering Technician/Production Assistant

April 2009 to October 2010

- Operated and troubleshot teleprompter, robotic studio cameras and copier equipment for multiple daily news programs.
- Ensured television personalities, when on air, were properly focused and composed for maximum viewer effect and attention.
- Prepared rundowns and scripts for television personalities' appearances on air.

University of Central Oklahoma; Edmond, OK

Part-time job

Student Anchor/Producer/Production Assistant

January to May 2009 and August to December 2009

- Prepared rundowns and scripts for student television anchors' appearances on air.
- Produced student news programs, including researching, rewriting, placing and assigning stories for said programs.
- Acted as floor director for daily news shows, ensuring camera operators properly focused and composed broadcast images of television personalities

EDUCATION

Earned bachelor of arts degree in liberal studies (mass communications emphasis) OKLAHOMA CITY UNIVERSITY; Oklahoma City, OK
Progress made toward B.A., mass communications (broadcasting emphasis) UNIVERSITY OF CENTRAL OKLAHOMA; Edmond, OK
Earned associate of applied science in information systems technology
COMMUNITY COLLEGE OF THE AIR FORCE; Maxwell Air Force Base, AL
Earned associate of applied science in communication applications technology
COMMUNITY COLLEGE OF THE AIR FORCE; Maxwell Air Force Base, AL
Earned associate of arts in Russian
DEFENSE LANGUAGE INSTITUTE; Presidio of Monterey, CA
Earned certification for Basic Public Affairs Specialist Course
DEFENSE INFORMATION SCHOOL; Fort George G. Meade, MD

REFERENCES

Available upon request.